<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Combat Effects for Combat Extended (Continued)</name>
  <packageId>Mlie.CombatEffectsforCE</packageId>
  <author>CalaveraLoca</author>
  <url>https://github.com/emipa606/CombatEffectsforCE</url>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.0</li>
    <li>1.1</li>
    <li>1.2</li>
    <li>1.3</li>
    <li>1.4</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>CETeam.CombatExtended</packageId>
      <displayName>Combat Extended</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2890901044</steamWorkshopUrl>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/CombatExtended-Continued/CombatExtended</downloadUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>CETeam.CombatExtended</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <description>[img]https://i.imgur.com/buuPQel.png[/img]
Update of CalaveraLocas mod
https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1756442393

- Added option to disable the extra blood-spatter
- Fixed the issues with the added mortar-ammo in later CE-versions
- The update for the 5.2-version of CE done by Taranchuk

[img]https://i.imgur.com/pufA0kM.png[/img]

[table]
	[tr]
		[td][url=https://dsc.gg/mlie][img]https://i.imgur.com/zdzzBrc.png[/img][/url][/td]
		[td][url=https://github.com/emipa606/CombatEffectsforCE][img]https://i.imgur.com/kTkpTOE.png[/img][/url][/td]
    [/tr]
    [tr]
        [td][img]https://i.imgur.com/WjDSfUn.png[/img][/td]
        [td][img]https://i.imgur.com/h5VwTNL.png[/img][/td]
    [/tr]
[/table]
	
[img]https://i.imgur.com/Z4GOv8H.png[/img]

This mod adds sparks to bullets impacting hard surfaces and blood effects for hitting pawns.
Now also allows bullets to penetrate materials.
Only works with Combat Extended.
IMPORTANT : Load it AFTER the Combat Extended mod.

[b]UPDATE[/b] June 10 : 
- Bugfixes (Hanging projectiles, NaN projectile position, inconsistent projectile position for logic and graphics)

Plans: 
[strike]-Add a few more effects (like dust/smoke puffs to impacts) - DONE [/strike]
- If possible add bullet ricochet and material penetration. :
- - - Penetration initial implementation done. Details below.
- Vanilla version.
- Make options available to tone the effects up or down

[b]Penetration mechanics[/b] :
Bullets have a chance to penetrate a build object based on caliber, ammo type and the material and condition of the object it hit.
Every projectile type has a base chance to penetrate a given material.

For example : a 9x19 FMJ has 10% chance to penetrate a wooden wall if that wall has 100% hitpoints.
It has 80% chance to penetrate that wall if it's below 50% hitpoints.
Meanwhile a 14.5x114 has 100% to penetrate that wall regardless it's hitpoints.

A steel wall is impenetrable by small arms when kept in good condition but the aforementioned 14.5 has 60% to penetrate it.

AP type bullet (Sabot, AP-I etc) has increased penetration stats.

Additionally, there is a slight randomness of these chances. So it's entirely possible for a .303 to penetrate a plasteel wall once in a lifetime.

However:
- HP bullets and energy projectiles never penetrate (for now).
- Arrows never penetrate (for now)

Bullets can penetrate pawns. It's a flat percentage. (Example 7.62x51 has 35% to penetrate the target).
So a singe .50BMG can ruin the day of several Alphabeavers in a bottleneck. But it can also ruin the day of allies behind those Alphabeavers.

Kinetic energy : WIP. Not enabled yet. But after each penetration or ricochet the bullet will loose some of it's energy so even if the projectile penetrates your walls it may do minimal damage.

Angle of Attack : WIP. Not enabled yet. Penetration chances as well as ricochet will additionally depend on the angle of incidence.

Important : I had to patch and decorate a lot of ammo defs for this. For now only ammo used by 'CE' and 'CE Guns' are patched. The others may be incompatible.




[img]https://media.giphy.com/media/Tcgk85vK91UEzLoc1R/giphy.gif[/img]


[img]https://i.imgur.com/PwoNOj4.png[/img]
[list]
[*] See if the the error persists if you just have this mod and its requirements active.
[*] If not, try adding your other mods until it happens again.
[*] Post your error-log using [url=https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=818773962]HugsLib[/url] or the standalone [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2873415404]Uploader[/url] and command Ctrl+F12
[*] For best support, please use the Discord-channel for error-reporting.
[*] Do not report errors by making a discussion-thread, I get no notification of that.
[*] If you have the solution for a problem, please post it to the GitHub repository.
[*] Use [url=https://github.com/RimSort/RimSort/releases/latest]RimSort[/url] to sort your mods
[/list]

[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/changelog/2172612733][img]https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/emipa606/CombatEffectsforCE?label=latest%20version&amp;style=plastic&amp;color=9f1111&amp;labelColor=black[/img][/url]</description>
  <modVersion IgnoreIfNoMatchingField="True">1.4.5</modVersion>
</ModMetaData>